

Md. Nahidul Islam Opu

- Mymensingh,Bangladesh +8801986980335
- ■ opu.nahidul@gmail.com
 - nahidul-opu.github.io
 - github | in linkedin

ABOUT ME

I am a student and a machine learning enthusiast. I have 2+ years of experience in game development using UnityEngine. I also have 2+ years of experience in research on machine learning. I am also interested in backend development. I am a quick learner who loves problem solving.

SKILLS _

- Proficient in Python, C#, C++
- Proficient in HTML, MySQL
- · Proficient in Git
- Proficient in Latex
- Proficient in Python Libraries: Pandas, Keras, Numpy etc
- OOP & Functional Programming
- Game Development (Unity Engine)

- Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Good understanding of data structure & algorithms
- Web Development
- Competitive programming: Codeforces (371)
- Familiar with Java, PHP, C, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, Django, Android Studio

EXPERIENCE

Research Experience

Working on Artificial Intelligence

- ·Bangla handwritten character recognition using CNN
- Augmented reality with machine learning
- •Covid-19 detection from chest X-ray using andorid application
- •Age and gender prediction using CNN. Published on IEEE Xplore

Arcade Studios

Intern Software Engineer

Arcade Studios

Junior Software Engineer (Part-time)

- · Worked as a game developer using Unity Engine
- Worked on Integration of Machine Learning into Game development

Nov 2019 - July 2020

July 2020 - October 2021

EDUCATION _

Chittagong University of Engineering and Technology

2017-Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

- Current CGPA: 3.46 (Up untill Level 3 Term II)
- · Working on Machine learning for undergraduate thesis

Govt. Ananda Mohan College, Mymensingh

H.S.C

• GPA: 5.00

Mymensingh Zilla School, Mymensingh

2006-2014

S.S.C

• GPA: 5.00

PROJECTS __

Learn to Write

Android application to teach handwriting to kids

Using Unity3D, C#, Python and ML Libraries

MediCare

An Andorid app to find doctor, hospital, ambulance with map

•Using Java, PHP, MySQL, Google Map API

Flower Classifier

An Andorid app to classify several types of flowers

- Using Unit3D, C#, Python and ML libraries
- Deployed on Heroku using flask

File Locker

File vault with face recognition

Using Python and ML Libraries

Machine Learning Algorithms

Pure Python implementation of several ML algorithms. Available in Github

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING

- Training on Machine Learning (Organized by CUET Sheikh Kamal IT Incubator)
- Applied Data Science with Python Specialization : Coursera
- Convolutional Neural Network: Coursera

AREA OF INTEREST _

Data Science | Software Development | Backend Development | Computer Vision

HOBBIES Reading Books | Watching Movies

2014-2016